Chia-Hsuan (Michael) Lee

☐ +1 669-204-2924 • ☑ chiahsuan.li@gmail.com in chiahsuanlee, chiahsuan156.github.io

Research interests:

My research interests are deep learning/machine learning and their applications in natural language processing. My recent research interests are open-domain question answering, conversational AI and language modeling. Broadly speaking, I am interested in language understanding and interpretability of deep learning models.

Education

University of Washington

Seattle, U.S.

Sep. 2019 -

PhD in Electrical and Computer Engineering,

Natural Language Processing Group, Advisor: Professor Mari Ostendorf - with Fellowship Fundings

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

Master, Computer Science,

Sep. 2017 - June, 2019

Advisors: Profs. Lin-shan Lee and Hung-Yi Lee

National Taiwan University

Taipei, Taiwan

B.S., Electrical Engineering, Advisor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

Sep, 2012 - Jan, 2017

Research Internship

o Natural Language Processing Team, Apple Inc., Cupertino, CA, July-Sep 2019

Publications (All as the First Author)

- [1] "Spoken SQuAD: A Study of Mitigating the Impact of Speech Recognition Errors on Listening Comprehension" Interspeech 2018 [Link]
 - Successfully construct a challenging spoken question answering(QA) dataset.
 - Utilize phonetic sub-word units to mitigate ASR errors and consistently improve SOTA QA model by 1.4% F1 score under different levels of noises.
- [2] "ODSQA: Open-Domain Spoken Question Answering Dataset" IEEE SLT 2018 [Link]
 - Collect the largest open domain spoken QA dataset.
 - Propose two data augmentation approaches: Text-to-Speech and Back-to-Back translation and improve SOTA QA model by 4% F1 score.
- [3] "Cross-Lingual Transfer Learning for Question Answering" [Link]
 - Incorporate Generative Adversarial Network to learn domain-invariant feature representations between English and Chinese.
 - Successfully bootstrap knowledge from English and achieve SOTA over a Chinese QA corpus, which outperforms previous best model by over 30 % F1 score.
- [4] "Mitigating the Impact of Speech Recognition Errors on Spoken Question Answering by Adversarial Domain Adaptation" ICASSP 2019 [Link]
 - Incorporate Generative Adversarial Network to adapt Reference Transcriptions domain to ASR hypotheses domain.
 - Outperform previous best model by 2% EM score.
- [5] "Towards Machine Comprehension of Spoken Content", IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing[Link]
 - Thorough study of QA models over two spoken QA corpora.
 - Select important sentences by using gated GRU and conduct multi-hop reasoning by long term memory component.

Honors and Awards

- o Electrical and Computer Engineering PhD Fellowship, University of Washington, Seattle
- Speech Technologies Research Scholarship, Committee of Advanced Speech Technologies (US\$16,000)
- o Artificial Intelligence Top Research Scholarship, Appier
- o Student Research Scholarship, Ministry of Science and Technology of Taiwan

Research and Teaching Experiences

Graduate Researcher, Speech Processing Lab

Taiwan

Advisors: Profs. Lin-Shan Lee and Hung-Yi Lee,

- Sep, 2017 Now
- Utilize learned phonetic representations to improve speech question answering model. [Interspeech]
- Utilize Back-to-Back translation system and Text-to-Speech system to improve speech question answering. **[IEEE SLT]**
- Propose an unified framework for cross-domain question answering and successfully achieved significant improvement on challenging cross lingual task and speech question answering task. **[ICASSP]**

Teaching Assistant Taiwan

National Taiwan University, Advanced Deep Learning [CSIE7430], Mar, 2018 – June, 2018

Design a challenging video caption generation task using CNN + RNN Seq-to-Seq.

Head Teaching Assistant

Taiwan

National Taiwan University, Machine Learning [EE5184], Sep. 2017 – Jan, 2018 Organize 19 teaching assistants and create 9 assignments for 353 students including text Sentiment classification(RNN+DNN, Semi-Supervised learning), movie recommendation(Matrix Factorization, DNN), chatbot(Seq-to-Seq) and speech translation(Kaldi, Retrieval Model, Seq-to-Seq). [Course Link]

Research Assistant, Speech Processing and Machine Learning Lab

Taiwan

Advisor: Prof. Hung-Yi Lee,

Utilize learned gating function and long-term memory to improve two speech question answering corpora.

[IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing]

Selected Projects

CSIE5130 Multimedia Analysis and Indexing

Taiwan

Sketch-based Image Retrieval across Art Styles, 2017 Sep – 2018 Jan Perform cross-domain image retrieval across different art styles using sketches as queries via hierarchical triplet CNN and triplet margin loss.

EE5047 Artificial Intelligence

Taiwan

Vision-based Deep Reinforcement Learning: Playing Atari Games, 2016 Sep – 2017 Jan Analyze the strength and weakness of Deep Q Learning(DQN), DoubleDQN and DuelingDQN in Atari Games

Relevant Coursework * denotes graduate-level course

Machine Learning / Artificial Intelligence

o Artificial Intelligence*, Machine Learning*, Applied Deep Learning*, Web Retrieval and Mining*, Data Science*, Digital Speech Processing*, Multimedia Analysis and Indexing*, Computer Vision*,

Fundamental Programming Courses

 Data Structure and Programming, Algorithms, the Design and Analysis of Algorithms*, Computer Programming, Embedded System, Computer Networks,

Skills

- Programming Languages: Python, C/C++, Matlab, R
- o Toolbox/Software: Tensorflow, Git, LATEX